Guide to the Scientific Research Society of Sigma Xi North America, Alpha Chapter records, 1886-1986.
Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society of North America, Alpha Chapter records, 1886-1986.
- Series IV. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Includes carbon copies of outgoing letters, correspondence, mimeographs, printed invitations, blank forms, Treasurer's Report
  - National Annual Meeting, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    Includes handwritten lists, officer and committee list, Agenda, Revisions to Constitution, Report of Ad Hoc Committee on Visit to Manhattan College, Attendance List, Reports on Grants-in-Aid and Lectureships
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes nomination list, by-laws (printed), Proceedings of Annual Convention, photocopied and mimeographed letters, membership lists, correspondence, carbon copies of outgoing letters, hotel reservation card, officer and committee list, bank interest income form
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence, mimeographs, carbon copies of outgoing letters, nomination blank and lists, change of address cards
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence, carbon copies of outgoing letters, mimeographs, nomination lists, hotel brochure, photocopy of handwritten list, other lists, handwritten notes, officer and committee lists
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes carbon copies of outgoing letters, correspondence, mimeographs, financial report forms, Executive Committee Minutes, nomination list, change of address forms
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence, banquet reservation cards, initiation ceremony program, typed manuscript on Sigma Xi history, carbon copies of outgoing letters, Nominating Committee Report, mimeographs, Annual Meeting Schedule and Program, Officer and Committee lists, nomination lists, Treasurer's Report, printed Initiation program
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes Nominating Committee Report, nomination lists, mimeographs, Executive Committee minutes, officer and committee list, blank notification of membership
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Includes carbon copies of outgoing letters, mimeographs
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Includes correspondence, carbon copies of outgoing letters, Treasurer's Report, nomination lists, printed program for Annual Convention, Proceedings of Annual Convention
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Includes correspondence, nomination list and blank, other lists, national Sigma Xi budget, national Sigma Xi President's Report, report to delegates of 1970 Annual Meeting, handwritten notes, Annual Meeting Agenda and Minutes, Treasurer's Report
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes correspondence, carbon copies of outgoing letters, handwritten notes
  - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Includes lists of officers and committees, carbon copies of outgoing letters, handwritten lists, correspondence, Travel Expense Report (blank), Treasurer's Annual Report, Annual Meeting minutes, press release (with photograph), printed invitations
  - Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence, photocopied bank deposit slips, carbon copies of outgoing letters, photocopied check, handwritten notes, report of Nominating Committee, printed Initiation program, lists
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes carbon copies of outgoing letters, correspondence, receipts, Treasurer's Report, Annual Meeting Minutes, Financial Report form, membership certificate order form, photocopied deposit slips, membership lists
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes nomination list, carbon copies of outgoing letters, membership certificate order form, correspondence, handwritten notes
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes correspondence, carbon copies of outgoing letters, Treasurer's Report, nomination lists
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Includes correspondence, Annual Meeting Agenda and Minutes, carbon copies of outgoing letters, Treasurer's Reports, Request Form for National Lecturer, Application for Grant-in-Aid of Research (several drafts), nomination lists, handwritten notes, officer and committee lists, Sigma Xi Certificate of Incorporation, printed Initiation program
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Includes carbon copies of outgoing letters, Executive Committee Meeting minutes (handwritten), correspondence, nomination list
  - Correspondence for Recording Secretary, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes Committee Questionnaire, handwritten notes, Annual Meeting Minutes, correspondence, Treasurer's Report, carbon copies of outgoing letters
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Includes correspondence, Annual Meeting Minutes and Treasurer's Report, carbon copies of outgoing letters, printed leaflet, handwritten notes, nomination list, list of officers, typescript photocopied manuscript - "Early Cornell naturalists and anatomists. Part I, 1867-1869" by Howard E. Evans
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Includes correspondence, nomination list, carbon copies of outgoing letters, printed leaflet - "Sigma Xi News," nomination blank, officer and committee lists, excerpts from chapter by-laws, handwritten notes, printed Errata and Index for 1974 Manual of Procedure, Procedure for Presenting Resolutions to the Assembly of Delegates at the National Meeting
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes correspondence, nominating committee selections
- Series V. Membership
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Includes changes of address, address labels, single-sheet brochure
  - Grants-in-Aid of Research, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Includes information sheets, application blanks, statistical summaries
  - Annual Convention, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Includes printed program, minutes, Treasurer's Report, committee reports, President's Report
  - Membership Lists, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1956 Roll, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1958 Roll, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1959 Roll, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Addressograph Changes, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Addressograph Changes, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1960 Roll, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 1961 Roll, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Addressograph Changes, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Addressograph Changes, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Additions to National Roll, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 1962 Roll, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 1963 Roll, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Additions to Roll, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Additions to Roll, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - National Roll, 1965-10 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - National Roll, 1965-12 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - National Roll, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Membership List, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Membership List, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - National Lists, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 1967 Roll, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 1968 Roll, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 1969 Roll, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Membership Lists, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Membership Lists, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Membership Lists, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership Lists, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Lists, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous National Sigma Xi associate to full membership, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence, handwritten notes
  - Two copies of the Plantations Newsletter with Fuertes Prize essay, 1982 (Box 7)
- Series VI. Administration
  - Manual of Procedure: incomplete, revised through 1963, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Manual of Procedure: incomplete, revised through 1963, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Manual of Procedure for Chapter and Club Officers of the Society of the Sigma Xi: revised through 1966, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Manual of Procedure for Chapter and Club Officers of the Society of the Sigma Xi: revised through 1966, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Manual of Procedure for Chapter and Club Officers of the Society of the Sigma Xi: revised through 1966, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Manual of Procedure for Chapter and Club Officers of the Society of the Sigma Xi: revised through 1966, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Manual of Procedure update, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Manual of Procedure for Chapter and Club Officers of the Society of the Sigma Xi: revised through 1969, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Manual of Procedure for Chapter and Club Officers of the Society of the Sigma Xi: revised through 1969, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Manuals of Procedure, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - By-Laws of the Alpha Chapter of the Society of the Sigma Xi, 1897-1954 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Constitution of the Society of the Sigma Xi, 1893-1904 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Report of the Committee for the Revision of the Constitution, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sigma Xi Constitution and By-Laws, 1922-1929 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sigma Xi History, Constitution and By-Laws, 1936-1942 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sigma Xi Song, Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sigma Xi Yearbooks: incomplete set, 1888-1948 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - The Society of the Sigma Xi and the Scientific Research Society of America (RESA) Official Information and Annual Reports, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Alpha Chapter of the Society of Sigma Xi Initiation Programs: incomplete set, 1922-1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Officers and Membership Prior to 1917 - Incomplete, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Includes statistical forms
  - General Information on Procedures, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Includes correspondence, proposed revisions to Constitution
  - Officers, Committees, Nominations, 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Includes handwritten notes, nomination blank, mimeographs, reports
  - Proposed Consolidation of the Sigma Xi and RESA, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Includes handwritten notes, correspondence, Resolution, carbon copies of outgoing letters
  - Information Concerning the Society of the Sigma Xi: for new members, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Proceedings of the Annual Convention, 1901-1912 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Proceedings of the Annual Convention, 1942-1965 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Proceedings of the Annual Convention, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Proceedings of the Annual Convention, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Proceedings of the Annual Convention, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Reports of Officers and Chairmen of Standing Committees to the 74th National Meeting, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Proceedings of the National Meeting, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Society of the Sigma Xi Semi-Centennial Celebration program, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Minutes, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Minutes, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Minutes, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Presidential Addresses (incomplete), 1887-1953 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Series VII. Petitions
  - Petitions for new chapters of Sigma Xi, 1909-1913 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Petitions, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Petitions, 1931-1935 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Petitions, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Petitions, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Petitions, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Petitions, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Petitions, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Petitions, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Petitions, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Petitions, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Petitions, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Petitions, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Petitions, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Petitions, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Petitions, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Petitions, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Petitions, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Petitions, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Petitions, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Series VIII. Nominations
  - Initiation Announcements, 1925-1945 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nominations A-D (completed forms), 1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Nominations E-H, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Nominations I-L, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Nominations M-P, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Nominations R-U, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Nominations V-Z, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Unclaimed certificates, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Nominations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Official Insignia and Order Forms, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Unclaimed certificates, official insignia and order forms, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Nominations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Nominations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Official Insignia and Order Forms, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Unclaimed certificates, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Nominations, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Nominations, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Nominations, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Unclaimed Certificates, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Official Insignia and Order Forms, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Nominations, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Nominations, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Nominations, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Official Insignia and Order Forms, handwritten list of initiates, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Series IX. Volumes
  - Vol I. Minutes of Cornell Chapter: 1st to 74th meetings, 1886-1901 (Box 7)
  - Vol II. Minutes of Cornell Chapter: 75th to 205th meetings, 1901-1917 (Box 7)
  - Petition for Sigma Xi chapter, University of Cincinnati, 1895 (Box 7)
  - Petition for Sigma Xi chapter, University of Cincinnati, 1898 (Box 7)
  - The Aims and Objectives of the Society of the Sigma Xi, 1914 (Box 7)
  - Sigma Xi - Alpha Chapter Treasurer's Accounts, 1887-1914 (Box 7)
  - Sigma Xi Cash Journal, 1914-1924 (Box 7)
  - Journal of the Cornell Chapter, 1953-1964 (Box 7)
  - Journal of the Cornell Chapter, 1964-1966 (Box 7)
  - Sigma Xi Half-Century Record and History, 1886-1936 (Box 7)
  - 7 rolls of 35mm negative film: Sigma Xi signature book, Undated; F-1923-1929 (Box 7)
  - Centennial Celebration, 1986 (Mapcase-folder 1)